Simon Flexner Papers 1891-1946 Mss.B.F365
American Philosophical Society
- Series I. Simon Flexner Papers, 1891-1946; 115.5 linear feet
  - Alexander, W.G.
  - Municipal Library
  - Alkus, William
  - Allan, John J.
  - Allard, Eva
  - Allard, H.A.
  - Allbutt, Sir Clifford, 1911-1921; 10 items
    Includes: Letters on Allbutt's suggestions for establishing an Institute for Comparative Physiology with Rockefeller Foundation funds. Flexner explains likely reaction of the Rockefeller Board, 1920.
  - Allegretti, Louis
  - Allen, A.
  - Allen, B. M.
  - Allen, Edmund T.
  - Allen, Edward S.
  - Allen, F.M.
  - Allen, Frederick H.
  - Allen, Frederick M.
  - Allen, George M.
  - Allen, Gertrude
  - Allen, H.W.
  - Allen, Sir Harry
  - Allen, J.B.
  - Allen, J.D.
  - Allen, Olive H.
  - Allen, Paul, Jr.
  - Allen, R.W.
  - Allen, S.C.
  - Allen, W.C.
  - Allen, William F.
  - Allen, William H.
  - Allen and Hanburys, Ltd.
  - Allerton House
  - Alleyne, Ernest
  - Alling, E.L.
  - Almirall, Raymond F.
  - Alpha Mu Pi Omega Medical Fraternity
  - Alsberg, Carl L., 1913-1920; 15 items
    Includes: Letters concerning staff of USDA Bureau of Chemistry. Letter requesting that SF find Prof. Weil of Germany a research position in U.S., 1919.
  - Alsever, William D.
  - Alter, Nicholas M.
  - Altof, Bertha
  - Altpeter, Julius
  - Aluskin, Ida
  - Alvarez, A.B.
  - Alvarez, Celestino
  - Alvarez, Mrs. V.B.
  - Alvarez, Walter C., 1931; ca. 5 items
    Includes: Alvarez requests suggestion for a young researcher in physiology to fill a Macy Foundation Fellowship at the Mayo Clinic.
  - Amaral, Afranio de
  - Amawalk Nursery
  - Ambrose, Lodilla
  - Amdur, M.K.
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences, 1912-1926; 5 items
    Includes: SF's election to the Academy, 1912; copy of the Academy's Statutes.
  - American Academy of Public Health, 1916; 1 item
    Includes: Notice of plans to form an academy; list of members.
  - American Arbitration Association
  - American Association for Experimental Pathology, 1912-1934; 12 items
    Includes: Notices of meetings, memoranda.
  - American Association for Highway Improvement
  - American Association for International Conciliation
  - American Association for Labor Legislation
  - American Association for Medical Progress, 3 folders
    Includes: Memoranda and articles on medical progress.
    - Folder 1, 1923-1925
    - Folder 2, 1926
    - Folder 3, 1927-1928
  - American Association for Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics, 1927-1935; 8 items
    Includes: Notices of meetings.
  - American Association for the Advancement of Science, 2 folders
    Includes: Notices of meetings of the Committee of One Hundred on Scientific Research; ballots, budgets, minutes, and memoranda.
    - Folder 1, 1914-1916
    - Folder 2, 1920-1933
  - American Association of Immunologists
  - American Association of Pathologists and Bacteriologists
  - American Blue Book
  - American Chemical Society
  - American College of Physicians
  - American Committee Against Fascist Oppression in Germany
  - American Committee to Aid Russian Scientists with Scientific Literature
  - American Congress on Internal Medicine
  - American Council of Learned Societies
  - American Epidemiological Society
  - American Express Company
  - American Foundation Studies in Government
  - American Friends Service Committee
  - American Geographical Society
  - American Hebrew
  - American Historical Association
  - American Homesteader
  - American Humane Association
  - American Institute
  - American Institute of Baking
  - American Jewish Committee
  - American Journal of Diseases of Children
  - American Journal of Public Health
  - American Journal of the Medical Sciences
  - American Kennel Club
  - American Laboratory Theatre
  - American Magazine
  - American Medical Association, 4 folders
    Includes: Request to SF to write a paper about animal experimentation for use by the new Hospital Section of the AMA, 1912. Requests to SF to give public lectures on current medical practices and legislation, 1912. Letters and grant proposals of Committee on Scientific Research; also general business correspondence.
    - Folder 1, 1911-1912
    - Folder 2, 1913-1914
    - Folder 3, 1915-1918
    - Folder 4, 1921-1940
  - American Medical Publishing Company
  - American Members of the Institut de France, Inc.
  - American Men of Science
  - American Mercury
  - American Museum of Natural History
  - American Neutral Conference Committee
  - American Philosophical Society, 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1916-1930
    - Folder 2, 1931-1934
    - Folder 3, 1938-1945
  - American Phytopathological Institute
  - American Press Association
  - American Public Health Association
  - American Red Cross
  - American Relief Administration
  - American Research Institute
  - American Scandinavian Foundation
  - American Society for Experimental Pathology
  - American Society for Pharmacology and Experimental Therapeutics
  - American Society for Psychical Research
  - American Society for the Prevention of Cruelty to Animals
  - American Type Culture Collection
  - American University of Beirut
  - American Zionist Medical Unit
  - Amerland, W.H.
  - Ames, A.F.
  - Ames, J.S., 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1913-1926
    - Folder 2, 1927-1937
  - Ameville, Dr.
  - Amos, Franklyn B.
  - Amos, Maurice S.
  - Amoss, Harold L., 17 folders
    Includes: Correspondence on Amoss' research on poliomyelitis and meningitis. Letters from Amoss to SF on his work on trench fever with the U.S. Army Medical Reserve Corps in France during WWI. Requests by SF for annual reports of his work at RIMR, 1916-1921. Administrative correspondence of RIMR. Letters on Amoss' poliomyelitis research conducted at the biological laboratory of the medical clinic of Johns Hopkins Hospital.
    - Folder 1, 1912-1915
    - Folder 2, 1916-1917
    - Folder 3, 1918
    - Folder 4, 1919
    - Folder 5, 1920
    - Folder 6, 1921
    - Folder 7, 1922
    - Folder 8, 1923
    - Folder 9, 1924
    - Folder 10, 1925
    - Folder 11, 1926
    - Folder 12, 1927
    - Folder 13, 1928
    - Folder 14, 1929-1930
    - Folder 15, 1931-1935
    - Folder 16, 1936-1942
    - Folder 17, n.d.
  - Amster, J. Lewis
  - Amster, Joseph S.
  - Anawati, Georges D.
  - Anders, James M.
  - Andersen, H.C.
  - Anderson, Ellen
  - Anderson, G.C.
  - Anderson, Grace M.
  - Anderson, Hamilton H.
  - Anderson, Howard B.
  - Anderson, J.L.
  - Anderson, J.S.
  - Anderson, James A.
  - Anderson, John F., 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1910-1917
    - Folder 2, 1926-1930
  - Anderson, Martha
  - Anderson, Nelson
  - Anderson, Paul Y.
  - Anderson, Robert
  - Anderson, W.W.
  - Anderson Galleries
  - Andervant, Howard B.
  - Andresen, Albert F.R.
  - Andrewes, C.H.
  - Andrews, Charles McLain
  - Andrews, Chase
  - Andrews, J.B.
  - Andrews, Justin
  - Andrews, W.L.
  - Androussieur, J.
  - Angell, James R.
  - Anigstein, Ludwik
  - Animal Experimentation
    - Anti-Vivisectionist Material, May 1932
    - Anti-Vivisectionist Material
    - Crank Letters
    - Dakin, H.D.
    - Flinn, Waldo R.
    - Newspaper Clippings
    - Smith, Edric B.
  - Anisfeld, Marella
  - Anson, Mortimer L.
  - Anspach, Brooks M.
  - Anti-Vivisection
  - Antones, Altino
  - Aoki, Kaoru
  - Apolant, Hugo
  - Appel, Theodore B.
  - Applebe, E.W.
  - Appleby, Frank L.
  - Applegate, Virginia
  - Appleget, Thomas B., 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1927-1928
    - Folder 2, 1929
    - Folder 3, 1930-1932
  - Appleton, Charles W.
  - Appleton and Co.
  - Appleton's Cyclopedia of American Biography
  - Applications
  - Appling, J.W.
  - Arafa, M.A.
  - Aragao, Henrique de B.
  - Araki, T
  - Araujo, H.C.
  - Arbuckle, A.M.
  - Archer, Ann
  - Archibald, Edward
  - Archibald, R.G.
  - Ard, Frank C.
  - Ardin
  - Argentine Embassy (Washington, D.C.)
  - Argnelles, M.V.
  - Arima Kenkyusho
  - Arizona Board of Health
  - Arkin, Aaron
  - Arkwright, Joseph A.
    Includes: Materials on viruses.
  - Armfield, Frank
  - Armit, H.W.
  - Armsby, Henry Prentiss, 1920-1921; 8 items
    Includes: Correspondence on Rockefeller Foundation grant to institute of Animal Nutrition at Pennsylvania State College. Two reports to SF outlining Armsby's projected work under the grant.
  - Armstrong, Alfred W.
  - Armstrong, Alice H.
  - Armstrong, Charles
  - Armstrong, Hamilton Fish
  - Armstrong, J. Wilbur
  - Armstrong, Richard
  - Army and Navy Club
  - Army Relief Society
  - Armyl, Gwilym
  - Arndt, H.W.
  - Arneill, James R.
  - Arnett, Trevor
  - Arnin, Elizabeth
  - Arnold, D.P.
  - Arnold, Iva Mae
  - Arnold, K.B.
  - Arnold, Lloyd
  - Arnold, Lucille R.
  - Arnstein, George
  - Aron, Max
  - Aronson, E.
  - Aronstrom, Noah E.
  - Arranz, Felipe
  - Arric, Lefevre de
  - Arroyo, Carlos F.
  - Arsonval, d'
  - Arthur, W. C.
  - Arthur Road Hospital
  - Arthus, Maurice
  - Artists and Writers Dinner Club
  - Aschoff, Ludwig, 1911-1935; 16 items
    Includes: Letters on Aschoffla trip to China, 1924; also general correspondence.
  - Ascoli, Alberto, 2 folders
    Includes: Letters concerning Ascoli's move to U.S., 1941; on exchange of reprints.
    - Folder 1, 1917-1940
    - Folder 2, 1941-1944
  - Ascoli, Maurizio
  - Ascoli, Vittorio
  - Ashburn, P. M.
  - Ashburn, S. M.
  - Ashby, Winifred
  - Asher, Leon, 1923-1925; 1932; 1 folder
    Includes: Letters from Asher to SF outlining research on the correlation between the capacity of animals to resist disease and the age of the animals.
  - Asheshov, Igor N.
  - Ashford, Bailey K., 1914-1926; 10 items
    Includes: Correspondence respecting a grant to aid Ashford to visit the Institute of Tropical Medicine, San Juan; also general correspondence.
  - Ashhurst, Astley P. C.
  - Ashkanazy, M.
  - Ashworth, Prof.
  - Asiatic Institute
  - Aspiazu, R
  - Assheton, Lydia
  - Assistance Publique de Bruxelles
  - Associated News
  - Association for the Prevention of Tuberculosis
  - Association of American Physicians, 1913-1914; 15 items
    Includes: Reports, memoranda and notes on meetings.
  - Astley, G.
  - Aston, Frederick A.
  - Astor, Waldorf
  - Astrom, Algot
  - Aswell, Edward C.
  - Atherton, Grant S.
  - Atherton, P. L.
  - Atkins, Charles D.
  - Atkins, W. C.
  - Atkinston, Walter S.
  - Atlanta (Ga.). Laboratory of Hygiene
  - Atlantic City (N.J.). Department of Health
  - Atlantic Monthly
  - "Atlantis"
  - Atlas, A.
  - Atlee, John L.
  - Atterbury, Grosvenor
  - Atwater, R. M.
  - Atwell, J. C.
  - Atwood, A. B.
  - Atwood, Albert W.
  - Atwood, Charles E.
  - Atwood, F. G.
  - Atwood, George G.
  - Atwood, Wallace
  - Aub, Joseph C
  - Audubon Prints
  - Auer, Clara Meltzer
  - Auer, John, 3 folders
    Includes: Periodic reports concerning Auer's work with dimethyl sulphate gas during WWI conducted at RIMR, 1916-19. Letters on exchange of reprints after Auer had moved to the Department of Pharmacy, Washington University, St. Louis; also general correspondence.
    - Folder 1, 1916-1919
    - Folder 2, 1920-1921
    - Folder 3, 1923-1934
  - Auerbach, Theodore H.
  - Augur, Alexander
  - Augustin, A.G.
  - Ault, J.
  - Auskulat, Dr.
  - Austin, J. Harold, 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1917-1923
    - Folder 2, 1926-1930
  - Austin, R.
  - Austin Riggs Foundation
  - Australian Institute of Tropical Medicine
  - Austria, Mödling Boys' School
  - Austrian, Charles R.
  - Austrian, Delia
  - Automobile
  - Autopsies
  - Avery, E.E.
  - Avery, Oswald T., 3 folders
    Includes: Informal notice of SF's approval of Avery's appointment to RIMR, 1913. General administrative correspondence on the RIMR, including many covering letters originally attached to reports, articles or reprints.
    - Folder 1, 1913-1922
    - Folder 2, 1924-1925
    - Folder 3, 1927-1945
  - Avison, Douglas B.
  - Axford, W. Homer
  - Ayars, C.W.
  - Ayars, James S.
  - Aycock, W. Lloyd, 2 folders
    Includes: Correspondence concerning Aycock's work on prevention of poliomyelitis. Requests for exchange of reprints.
    - Folder 1, 1916-1928
    - Folder 2, 1929-1932
  - Aydelotte, Frank
  - Ayer, James B.
  - Ayer, Wardner D.
  - Ayrout, Salim Bey
  - Ayuso, H.
  - Azzi, Azzo
  - Azagra, Pio
  - B. Login and Son
  - Babbitt, Ellen C.
  - Babcock, Miss
  - Babcock, E.J.
  - Babcock, Frederick W.
  - Babcock, Gertrude
  - Babcock, H.E.
  - Babcock, J.W.
  - Babcock, Robert H.
  - Babcock, Stephen Moulton, 1920; 2 items
  - Babcock, William
  - Babers, Frank H.
  - Babes, Victor
  - Babkin, B.
  - Babogal, Julio
  - Bach, Alexander
  - Bacharach, Max
  - Bachman, Frank H.
  - Bachmann, C.
  - Bachmann, Robert A.
  - Bachmeyer, A.C.
  - Bachrach, Inc.
  - Bacillus Welchii Antitoxin
  - Backstrand, J.F.
  - Bacon, C.B.
  - Bacon, E.W.
  - Bacon, Gorham
  - Bacon, Raymond F.
  - Bacon, Susan Randall
  - Badger, Philip O.
  - Baehr, George
  - Baer, Almeria W.
  - Baer, Flora
  - Baer, William S.
  - Baeslack, Frederick W.
  - Baetjer, Frank H.
  - Bagg, Halsey J.
  - Bagley, Charles, Jr.
  - Bagné, Jaime
  - Bagshawe, Arthur Z.
  - Bahme, Harold
  - Bail, Oskar
  - Bailey, Charles H.
  - Bailey, E.P.
  - Bailey, Esther S.
  - Bailey, Frederick C.
  - Bailey, George W.
  - Bailey, Harold
  - Bailey, Harry D.
  - Bailey, John H.
  - Bailey, Marshall H.
  - Bailey, P.S.
  - Bailey, Pearce
  - Bailey, Walter C., 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1915-1917
    - Folder 2, Jan.-Apr. 1918
    - Folder 3, May-Aug. 1918
  - Bailey, William
  - Bailey, William H.
  - Bain, J.M.
  - Bain, James, 12 folders
    - Folder 1, 1913-1924
    - Folder 2, 1925-1926
    - Folder 3, 1927
    - Folder 4, 1928
    - Folder 5, 1929-1930
    - Folder 6, 1931
    - Folder 7, 1932
    - Folder 8, 1933
    - Folder 9, 1934
    - Folder 10, 1935
    - Folder 11, 1936-1939
    - Folder 12, 1940-1944
  - Bainbridge, William Seaman
  - Baird, Alvin W.
  - Baird, Ben D.
  - Baird, Frederick H.
  - Baiz, E.
  - Baker, Benjamin
  - Baker, Carl J.
  - Baker, David
  - Baker, Joseph J.
  - Baker, Lillian E., 1922-1932; 6 items
    Includes: Letter to SF accepting a research position under Alexis Carrel, 1922.
  - Baker, Newton D.
  - Baker, Robert P.
  - Baketel, H.S.
  - Bakker, S.
  - Balch, Albert S.
  - Balch, Barbara S.
  - Balch, Earle H.
  - Baldauf, Leon K.
  - Baldauf, Trude
  - Baldwin, Mrs. Austin R.
  - Baldwin, E.F.
  - Baldwin, Edward R.
  - Baldwin, Herbert B.
  - Baldwin, I.L.
  - Baldwin, L.D.
  - Baldwin, L.O.
  - Baldwin, William H.
  - Balfour, Andrew
  - Balfour, Eve B.
  - Balfour, Grace
  - Balfour, J. Vincent
  - Ball, Bertram
  - Ball, [Bertha] C.
  - Ball, Halsey J.
  - Ball, Mable F.
  - Ball, T.R.
  - Ballard, Mrs. W.J.
  - Ballentine, Mary.
  - Balls, A.K.
  - Balme, Harold
  - Balsiger, Mrs. J.A.
  - Bamford, M.W.
  - Bancker, William F.
  - Bancroft, Joseph
  - Bancroft, Wilder Dwight, 1919-1932; 20 items
    Includes: Administrative correspondence of National Research Council Fellowship Board in physics, chemistry, and mathematics.
  - Banerjee, C.
  - Bangs, L. Bolton
  - Banks, Edgar J.
  - Banks, George S.
  - Banting, Frederick Grant, 1923-1937; ca. 50 items
    Includes: Correspondence concerning production of insulin. Requests for exchange of reprints. Recommendations of various persons for employment or grants.
  - Bantz, G.W.
  - Banzhof, Henry L.
  - Barach, Joseph H.
  - Barany, Dr.
  - Barber, C.F.
  - Barber, Marshall A.
  - Barbour, Henry G.
  - Barbour, Thomas, 1922-1925; ca. 60 items
    Includes: Correspondence concerning the fight of the Friends of Medical Progress against the anti-vivisectionists.
  - Barbour, W. Warren
  - Barcroft, Joseph, 1933-1934; 4 items
    Includes: Letters concerning his nephew working on staff of RIMR, 1934.
  - Bardach, Bruno
  - Bardeen, C.R.
  - Barendrecht, G.
  - Barger, George
  - Barjot
  - Barker, Creighton
  - Barker, Grace S.
  - Barker, Lewellys F., 7 folders
    Includes: Letters concerning his research on diptheria at Johns Hopkins Hospital. Personal correspondence on Barker's treatment of Flexner family members. Letters concerning SF's biography of W. H. Welch.
    - Folder 1, 1910-1916
    - Folder 2, 1917-1918
    - Folder 3, 1919-1920
    - Folder 4, 1921-1925
    - Folder 5, 1928-1930
    - Folder 6, 1931-1942
    - Folder 7: Notes on Constipation, n.d.
  - Barker, Lilian H.
  - Barker, Marion F.
  - Barker, W. Halsey
  - Barlow, Ellen Shaw
  - Barlow, H.M.
  - Barlow, Sir Montague
  - Barlow, Sir Thomas
  - Barlow, W. Jarvis
  - Barnard Free Skin and Cancer Hospital
  - Barnes, George E.
  - Barnes, Harry A.
  - Barnes, Henry B.
  - Barnes, Ralph E.
  - Barnes and Noble
  - Barnesby, Norman
  - Barnswell, Madge B.
  - Barnum, H.W.
  - Baron, Richard
  - Barret, Cecil
  - Barrett, Sir James
  - Barrier, Charles W.
  - Barrow, Woolfolk
  - Barrows, Albert L., 8 folders, ca. 300 items
    Includes: Correspondence, memoranda, notes and minutes concerning the National Research Council (NRC) Division of Educational Relations; also materials relating to the reorganization of NRC, 1932-1933. Copies of comments on the fellowship programs of NRC by various members of the Fellowship Board, 1934.
    - Folder 1, 1919-1922
    - Folder 2, 1923-1928
    - Folder 3, 1929
    - Folder 4, 1931-1932
    - Folder 5, 1933
    - Folder 6, 1934
    - Folder 7, 1935
    - Folder 8, 1936-1942
  - Barrows, Edward M.
  - Barrows, Paul M.
  - Barry, Adrienne
  - Barscoumian, Yervant
  - Barsky, Edward K.
  - Bartelt, Arthur N.
  - Barth, Otto
  - Bartine, Oliver H.
  - Bartlett, A.R.
  - Bartlett, C.J.
  - Bartlett, F.H.
  - Bartlett, Lyman
  - Bartley, William
  - Barton, Henry A.
  - Barton, James L.
  - Bartow, Edward
  - Baruch, Bernard M.
  - Baruch, Herman B., 1910; 2 items
    Includes: Letters outlining his ideas relating to pneumonia toxin and serum, in which Baruch states that anti-toxin can be produced from white corpuscles of infected patients.
  - Basch, Carl
  - Bascom, F.
  - Bashford, E.F.
  - Bashford, J.W.
  - Baskerville, Charles
  - Bass, C.C., 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1911-1920
    - Folder 2, 1923-1925
    - Folder 3, 1926
  - Bass, L.W.
  - Bass, Robert P.
  - Bassett, L.E.
  - Bassett, V.H.
  - Bassett-Smith, P.W., 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1916-1918
    - Folder 2, 1919-1920
  - Bassoe, Peter
  - Bastai, Pio
  - Bastedo, W.A.
  - Bastian, C.C.
  - Bastian, Jacob J.
  - Bastianelli, Guiseppe
  - Bastianelli, R.
  - Batchelder, A.P.
  - Batchelder, N.H.
  - Batchelor, Bronson
  - Batchelor, Marjory D.
  - Batchelor, Roger P.
  - Bates, Lewis B.
  - Bates, William N.
  - Bath, Joseph
  - Batman, R.A.
  - Batten, Fred E.
  - Battistini, Telemaco
  - Baudisch, Oskar, 3 folders
    - Folder 1, 1923-1925
    - Folder 2, 1926-1927
    - Folder 3, 1928-1934
  - Bauer, Adelia
  - Bauer, Edward L.
  - Bauer, John T.
  - Bauer, W.W.
  - Bauerberg, P.J.
  - Baug, Ivar
  - Baumann, Louis
  - Baumann, Oscar I.
  - Baumhoff, Mrs. F. W.
  - Bausch and Lomb
  - Baxter, Donald E.
  - Baxter, Gregory P.
  - Baxter, James P. III
  - Bay, M.C.
  - Bayliss, William Maddock, 1921; 5 items
  - Bayly, Augustus G.
  - Bayne-Jones, Stanhope, 2 folders
    - Folder 1, 1920-1931
    - Folder 2, 1932-1937
  - Baynes, Ernest H.
  - Baynes, G.H.
  - Baynton, Alice M.
  - Bayon, H.
  - Beach, J.R.
  - Beadle, S.D.
  - Beadle, R.C.
  - Beaghler, Amos L.
  - Beagle, Fenimore W.
  - Beal, Jeannette
  - Beale, J.E.
  - Beall, Charles G.
  - Beall, K.H.
  - Bean, Donald P.
  - Bean, James R.
  - Bean, Mary Cloud
  - Bear, Harry
  - Beard, C.A.
  - Beard, J. Howard
  - Beard, R.V.
  - Beard, S.D.
  - Beasley, David
  - Beardsley, Mable R.
  - Beates, Henry, Jr.
  - Beatson, J.W.
  - Beattie, J.M.
  - Beaufils, Emilio
  - Beauvarlet, Auguste
  - Beaux, Cecilia
  - Beaver, Grace M
  - Becerra, Leon
  - Becht, Frank C
  - Beck, Carl
  - Beck, Gilbert M
  - Beck, Isabel
  - Beck, Joseph C
  - Becker, Carl
  - Becker, Elery R
  - Becker, Florence
  - Becker, Louis
  - Beckerman, Y.
  - Beckett, Gordon
  - Beckwith, T.D.
  - Becton, Dickinson and Co.
  - Beddre, A.E.
  - Bedford, J. Claude
  - Beebe, Robert C.
  - Beebe, S.P.
  - Beekman, Fenwick
  - Beer, Edwin
  - Beer, James A.
  - Beers, Clifford W.
  - Beeuwkes, Henry
  - Beggs, Felice M.
  - Behadur, Harinath Ghosh
  - Behan, Richard J.
  - Behnake, Norman L.
  - Behrend, Ernst R.
  - Behringwerke
  - Beilby, George E.
  - Beitz, Charles B.
  - Beitzke
  - Belais, Diana
  - Belfanti, Serafino
  - Belfield, H. Conway
  - Belgium
    - Académie Royale de Médecine de Belgique
    - Belgium. Ambassade. United States.
    - Société Belge de Médecine
  - Belisch, Marjory
  - Belknap, Chauncey
  - Bell, Albert J.
  - Bell, Arthur F.
  - Bell, Blair
  - Bell, Gordon
  - Bell, Howard H.
  - Bell, J.F.
  - Bell, Stuart
  - Bell, William B.
  - Bell, William H.
  - Bellairs, Mrs. C
  - Bellei, Guiseppe
  - Bellet, Jean
  - Belnovski, G.
  - Belt, Alvin G.
  - Beltran, Enrique
  - Bemelmans, E.
  - Benario, J.
  - Benchetrit, A.
  - Benderson, Herman N.
  - Benedict, Francis Gano, 1919-1932; 34 items
    Includes: Letters to SF on the fate of I. Pavlov in Russia. Letters on the election of H. P. Armsby to National Academy of Sciences. Letters on B. P. Babkin and the threat of his expulsion from Russia.
  - Benedict, Ralph C.
  - Benedict, W.L.
  - Benedikt, L.
  - Beneke, R.
  - Bengal Immunity Co.
  - Bengis, Esther
  - Benington, Arthur
  - Benjamin, Marcus
  - Benner, Richard S.
  - Bennett, A.B.
  - Bennett, G.E.
  - Bennett, James
  - Bennett, Jean
  - Bennezon, Louis
  - Benson, Allan L.
  - Benson, Revel A.
  - Bentley, G.M.
  - Bentley, Gwen
  - Bentley, J.
  - Bentley, Madison
  - Bentner, R.
  - Benton, Florence Y.
  - Bentz, Charles A.
  - Berczeller, L.
  - Berens, Conrad
  - Berenson, Bernard
  - Berenson, Mary
  - Berg, H.W.
  - Berg, W.N.
  - Berger, E.
  - Berger, G.A.
  - Bergey, D.H.
  - Berghausen, Oscar
  - Berghoff, Emanuel
  - Berglund, Hilding
  - Bergman, Charles Stewart
  - Bergmann, Hugo
  - Bergmann, Max, 1933-1942; 35 items
    Includes: Letters concerning Bergmann's appointment to RIMR; also scientific and professional correspondence.
  - Bergstrand, Hilding
  - Berkenfield, M.E.
  - Berkley, Henry J.
  - Berkowitz, Samuel
  - Berlin, Samuel
  - Berliner, Emile
  - Berman, H.W.
  - Berman, Ruth
  - Bermann, Maurice
  - Bermuda Biological Station
  - Bernanke, Max
  - Bernays, Edward L.
  - Bernhardt, Joseph
  - Bernheim, Alice Ida
  - Bernheim, Bernard
  - Bernsee, F.L.
  - Bernstein, E.P.
  - Bernstein, F.
  - Bernstein, Harry S.
  - Bernstein, Herman
  - Berry, C.S.
  - Berry, George P.
  - Berry, H.B.
  - Berry, James
  - Berry, Jane L.
  - Berry, John T.
  - Berry, R.E.
  - Berry, Virginia H.
  - Berthel, A.
  - Bertholet, William S.
  - Bertrand, G.
  - Berwanger, Recha
  - Besredka, A.
  - Bessau, Dr.
  - Bessemans, A.
  - Best, Marshall
  - Best, Victor C.
  - Best, William H.
  - Beston, Arthur E.
  - Beth, Karl
  - Betten, Cornelius
  - Bettmann, Edgar
  - Beurekdjiau, Dr.
  - Beutner, R.
  - Bevan, Alexander
  - Bibb, L.B.
  - Bibb, Lewis
  - Bibliographical Notes
  - Bicak, Joseph F.
  - Bickel, A.
  - Bicknell, Ernest P.
  - Biddle, Francis
  - Biddle, Grace
  - Bier, Mike
  - Bigdy, Kenolm H.
  - Bieber, Joseph
  - Bierbaum, C.H.
  - Bierwith, J.C.
  - Bigelow, Frederick S.
  - Bigelow, George H.
  - Bigelow, Henry B.
  - Bigelow, W.F.
  - Biggar, H.F.
  - Biggs, Hermann M., 8 folders
    Includes: Letters on additional endowment of RIMR by John D. Rockefeller, 1913. Letters on outbreak of polio among children in New York State, 1916. Circular letters to health.officers on action to be taken by N.Y. State Department of Health in regard to vaccination against several diseases, 1917. Copies of amendments to New York State Sanitary Code. Letters outlining qualifications for health officer of New York State. Report of the Sanitary Commission in Europe, 1917.
    - Folder 1, 1913-1914
    - Folder 2, 1915-1916
    - Folder 3, 1917
    - Folder 4, 1918
    - Folder 5, 1919